# Dominic J Mitchell

1-401-440-3243 Providence, RI Area dominic.joseph.mitchell.2018@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dominic-j-mitchell https://github.com/DominicJosephMitchell

Full Stack Web Developer, Specializing in Front End Web Design. A business professional enthusiastic about tech while constantly learning, and stretching the borders of my mind. Graduate of (IEL) Institute of Entrepreneurship & Leadership, Rhode Coders Web Development, and (GA) General Assembly. With 30 years experience in Management, Leadership, Construction & eight years Technology skills.

## **Employment History**

Web Design & Developer FellowGA – General Assembly10/2018-present\*Twelve week web development immersive program (600hrs plus)Advanced Support Center Engineer ICox Communications01/2013-06/2018\*Lead and trainer, tester new deployments, procedure development, voice, data, video support, networkingApplications Specialist – III Lead/TrainerUp-Source01/2012-12/2012\*Supporting 3rd party software and hardware applications: troubleshooting, break fix, install.TMC11/2010-01/2012

**Consultant/Tech**\*Advice and expertise: management, structure and strategy, IT, marketing, design, build-outs.

Founder / Entrepreneur Mitchell Construction Inc 04/2004-11/2010

\*Design/development, sales, consulting, marketing strategies, Project Management, Leadership.

#### **Education**

Institute – of – Entrepreneurship & Leadersl	hip	2018
*HTML – CSS – JavaScript	Web Design & Development	
<b>New Horizons Computer Learning Center</b>		2011
*A+, Net+, Sec+, MCP&MCDST	Network Support Technician	
Community College of Rhode Island		2003
*Associates in Arts Degree		

# **Technical Skills**

Proficient: Familiar:

HTML, CSS, wire-frames, Bootstrap, handlebars, AWS, Ruby on Rails, SQL Scrum/Agile, Git-Hub, Bash, express.js, back-end API's, SASS, Ajax, jQuery React, JavaScript, Mongoose, MongoDB JSON, Node.js

## Web Development Projects https://dominicjosephmitchell.github.io/DJMPortfolio/

- \*Bucket List: Things you'd love to do with your life, Let's get 'em on paper! Integrate with a third-party location-based API to allow users to search for a location or venue to add to their bucket list items. (using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Leaflet (map), Ajax, MongoDB, Mongoose and express.js)
- \*Trails: Welcome to Southern New England Trails, create an index of the trails that you have experienced. (using HTML/CSS/React//MongoDB/Mongoose, and express.js)
- \* Tic Tac Toe: A custom front-end JavaScript game engine which connects with a third-party API.
- \* Vacations: Multi-page user experience designed photo album for your viewing pleasure. (using HTML, CSS)
- \* Family Tree: Ancestry database for creation and storing of family data. Add your family tree. (using HTML, CSS, JavaScript)